icivics.org 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy | iCivics

iCivics Inc. (“iCivics”) is firmly committed to respecting the privacy rights of all visitors to our website at [www.icivics.org](http://www.icivics.org/%22%20%5Co%20%22www.icivics.org) or any successor website (the ‘”Website”). The following privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) applies when you make a donation to iCivics, either online or otherwise, when you visit the Website, when you use our software, or otherwise share your personal information with iCivics (collectively, our “Services”).  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as we wish to help you better understand the information we gather, how we handle it, how we disclose it, and your options regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, this information. This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time in order to address new issues and reflect changes on our Website. All changes will be posted here. Additionally, if the changes are material, we will provide notice through this Website or by other means and obtain consent before implementing such changes. By accessing, using or visiting the Website, you agree to be bound by all the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy as posted at the time of your access, use or visit. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please stop using this Website. We can provide hard copies of this Privacy Policy upon request.

## what personal information we collect

Our Services allow visitors and members to learn about and interact with iCivics. iCivics collects personal information about you such as your name and email address only if you voluntarily submit it to us (collectively, “personal information”). We automatically collect other information relating to your visit to our Website, such as your IP address, the server into which your computer is logged on, your browser type, operating system, browser language, and service provider (collectively, “automatically collected information”). We may store and use information that you provide or that we automatically collect to keep you updated about our work, analyze usage of the Website, and improve our content, layout, and services.  

 If you receive communications from us, it is because we believe you may be interested in the events and activities of the iCivics. If you prefer not to receive promotional e-mail messages or other communications from us, please reply to the e-mail message with "remove" in the subject line or write to us asking to have your email address removed from our mailing list and we will do so.

## how we collect your personal information

iCivics obtains information from you either by you typing in your personal details or by the automatic collection of information through Google Analytics as you use our Services. We collect and store information that you provide or that we automatically collect and use it for the purposes for which you submitted it. In addition, we may use such information to keep you updated about our work, analyze usage, and improve our Service’s content, layout, and services. We may also use automatically collected information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts.

##  **disclosure of your information to third parties**

iCivics will never sell your information to third parties. We reserve the right to employ companies to assist us with such functions as hosting our donor information database, sending postal mail and e-mail, modeling our data, organizing fundraiser events, processing online and mail donations and credit card payments and to perform various administrative tasks. These companies may have access to personally identifying information about you, but only to the extent needed to perform their functions. iCivics requires that these companies keep such information confidential, to use it only for the purpose authorized by you, and to delete this information after performing these services. In case iCivics or one of our affiliates is acquired, we may transfer personal information to the successor, provided that the successor is subject to these same privacy commitments for previously collected personal information. Please be advised that we may disclose personally identifying information about you to the government or to third parties pursuant to law enforcement inquiries, court orders, subpoenas and similar requests, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary or appropriate in connection with any activity that violates the law or may expose us to liability. 

## disclosure of your identity on our website

If you become a member of iCivics, you will have a secure public name that will be displayed to other users. If you join an iCivics "class" by entering a leader code, you will be asked to enter your first name and last initial, which will be displayed to the owner of that leader code. Please only enter a leader code that has been given to you by an educator whom you know. Users may not post information pertaining to their identity or other personal items on our site. 

## accessing, editing, and deleting your personal information

If you provide iCivics with personal information, you may access and edit this information at any time by visiting the “Edit Account” link at the top right corner of the Website. If you would like to request deletion of your account, please email us at [feedback@iCivics.org](mailto:feedback@iCivics.org). iCivics may delete the accounts of users who have not signed into the Website for 12 months. 

## security

The personally identifying information that you provide is stored in a secure location, including on password controlled servers which are accessible only by designated employees who are trained in the proper handling of such personally identifying information. iCivics regularly assesses and adjusts the safeguards it uses to protect your information. You should be aware, however, that "perfect security" does not exist; third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications and iCivics makes no representation, warranty or guarantee that our Services are protected from viruses, security threats or other vulnerabilities or that your information will always be secure. You hereby acknowledge that we are not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the Internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorized manner. If we become aware of any security breach which we know has resulted in unauthorized access of your personally identifying information, then we will endeavor to inform you of that breach as soon as it is practicable for us to do so; however, this notification may be delayed while law enforcement conducts any investigation. 

## cookies

Cookies are small text files that a website transfers to a website visitor's hard disk or browser for added functionality, or for tracking website usage. We use cookies in a limited capacity (e.g., cookies "expire" at the end of your user session). Our cookies do not capture or store any personally identifying information about you, or any data about your past usage of our Website. We use information captured by cookies only for de-identified statistical analysis, and to tailor our communications with the public.

## NOTE TO PARENTS AND CHILDREN 

iCivics welcomes children to learn more about our organization and about the educational issues presented on our Website, and we are particularly respectful of the privacy of our young users. We encourage parents to monitor their children's use of the Internet and to help us protect their privacy by instructing them never to provide personal information on this Website or any of our Services without permission. We will never attempt to extract unnecessary information from our users, regardless of age. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), we will never knowingly request personally identifying information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If a child under the age of 13 wishes to sign up for a user account on our Website, he or she must first obtain parental approval and provide a parent's email address for confirmation. As soon as we receive email confirmation from the parent's email address approving the child's user account, we will activate the account. The consenting parent or guardian may monitor the collected information, revoke permission to use previously collected personal information, or delete his or her child’s account by contacting us at feedback@icivics.org. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with such information without consent, we will use our best efforts to remove such information from our files. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that a child under 13 has provided such information to us, he or she should contact us at [feedback@icivics.org](mailto:feedback@icivics.org) so that we may deactivate the user account and remove all personally identifying information from our Website and servers.

## privacy policy changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, so it is advisable to review it frequently. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be announced on our Website, and all non-material amended terms shall automatically be effective immediately. If the changes are material, we will provide notice through email, this Website, or other means and obtain consent before implementing such changes.  

## contact information

If you have questions about our handling of personal information, you may write to us at [feedback@icivics.org](mailto:feedback@icivics.org) or at the address below.

## mailing address

iCivics, Inc. is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt nonprofit located at 1035 Cambridge Street, Suite 21B, Cambridge, MA 02141.

This privacy policy is effective as of May 16, 2010.

## governing law

You agree that your use of this Privacy Policy and any disputes relating thereto shall be governed in all respects by the laws of the State of New York. Any dispute relating to this Privacy Policy shall be resolved solely in the state or federal courts located in Manhattan, New York. This Privacy Policy was last updated on July 27, 2015.
